The fastest hands in the East meet the biggest mouth in the West.
Rush Hour is a action, comedy, crime film directed by Brett Ratner.
When Hong Kong Inspector Lee is summoned to Los Angeles to investigate a kidnapping, the FBI doesn't want
any outside help and assigns cocky LAPD Detective James Carter to distract Lee from the case.
Not content to watch the action from the sidelines, Lee and Carter form an
unlikely partnership and investigate the case themselves.
Lee, played by Jackie Chan.
Carter, played by Chris Tucker.
Griffin, played by Tom Wilkinson.
Captain Diel, played by Philip Baker Hall.
Johnson, played by Elizabeth Peña.
Clive, played by Chris Penn.
Rush Hour is a 1998 American buddy cop action comedy film directed by Brett Ratner
from a screenplay by Jim Kouf and Ross LaManna and a story by LaManna.
It stars Jackie Chan, Chris Tucker, Tom Wilkinson,
Chris Penn, and Elizabeth Peña.
In the film, Hong Kong Police Force (HKPF) Chief Inspector Lee (Chan) and Los Angeles Police Department (LAPD)
Detective James Carter (Tucker) are forced to work together to rescue a Chinese diplomat's abducted daughter.
Development on Rush Hour began in 1995, after LaManna wrote a spec script, which was first
initially sold to Hollywood Pictures with Ratner and Chan both attached to the project.
The film was eventually shelved until being acquired by New Line Cinema, who had an
established relationship with Ratner and Tucker following Money Talks (1997).
Several actors were considered prior to Tucker signing onto the
project, with the rest of the cast rounded out by early 1997.
Principal photography began that November and lasted until January 1998, with
filming locations including California, Los Angeles and Hong Kong.
Rush Hour was theatrically released in the United States
on September 18, 1998, by New Line Cinema.
The film received mixed-to-positive reviews from critics, with
praise for Tucker and Chan's chemistry and performances.
It also grossed $245.3 million worldwide and was followed by two
sequels: Rush Hour 2 (2001) and Rush Hour 3 (2007).
The film explores themes of martial arts, fbi, two man army, chinese mafia, cop.
The tone is lighthearted.